http://www.ihs.ac.at/services-for-ihs-members/privacy-policy/

Public Relations | Newsletter | Contact
EN
DE
NewsletterAboutMission StatementOrganizationHistoryMembershipsKunst@IHSAnja Manfredi 2018/2019AlumniPalais StrozziSeminar Rooms for RentPublic RelationsNewsPress ReleasesLogosIHS Terms and ConditionsJob OpeningsContactResearchResearch PrioritiesResearch UnitsTools, Models, DataEconomic Forecast AustriaJoint Economic ForecastEconomic High-Frequency MonitorEuropean Social Survey (ESS) AustriaEUROSTUDENTModelsToolsResearch PlatformsGender and DiversityScience Goes PublicSocio-Ecological TransformationSocial Sciences HistoryTransport and MobilityDoctoral CollegeDoctoral CandidatesFormer CurriculaPeopleIHS - PeopleSpotlightFellowsArchiveEventsUpcoming EventsHeinrich Neisser Lecture2020: Geldpolitik im Wandel2019: Europa - die beste Idee, die wir je hatten2018: Zukunft der Arbeit im Digitalen Zeitalter2017: Sustainable DevelopmentLange Nacht der ForschungConference SeriesForecasting WorkshopVienna Macroeconomics WorkshopATHEA ConferencesÖGOR-IHS WorkshopsTime Series WorkshopsEvent Reviews2020201920182017Event ArchivePublications HubRepository IRIHSBlogPolicy BriefsLibraryNew BooksArticlesDatabasesJournalsPeopleOpen AccessPolicies of Funding BodiesPublisher AgreementsInformation for AuthorsRepositoriesHealth System WatchEmpirical EconomicsServices for IHS MembersImpressumPrivacy PolicySitemapRepresentativesEmployee RepresentativesIKIT ServicesUsers and VisitorsEmail and CalendarMiscellaneousNetwork AccessRestricted AccessPeopleWebmailLogin (Personal Page)Email alert service
About
Mission Statement
Organization
History
Memberships
Kunst@IHS
Alumni
Palais Strozzi
Privacy Policy
General informationThe protection and security of your personal information are very important to us. The website of the Institut für Höhere Studien - Institute for Advanced Studies (IHS) hereinafter referred to as IHS, stores and processes data in line with the General Data Protection Regulation and the Austrian Data Protection Act. By accessing our website you consent to our website accessing and processing your data. If other websites with the ihs.ac.at domain or its subdomains do not state a separate data protection policy, then this declaration also applies to them.The data collected are not transmitted to third parties.Name and contact details of the responsible party and their representativeDr. Martin Kocher, DirectorDr. Eva Liebmann-Pesendorfer, MPA, GeschäftsführerinInstitut für Höhere Studien – Institute for Advanced Studies (IHS), Josefstädter Straße 39, 1080 Vienna, AustriaName and contact details of the data protection officerMag. Harald HutterInstitut für Höhere Studien – Institute for Advanced Studies (IHS), Josefstädter Straße 39, 1080 Vienna, Austriadatenschutz(at)ihs.ac.atData that is processed when visiting the websiteThe following data is automatically stored and processed when you visit our website:Server logs: Server logs store the IP address of the site visitor along with data on the time and history of page requests, the amount of data transferred, whether the retrieval was successful, the identification of the browser data and operating system used, as well as the website from which it was accessed (in case it was accessed via a link) .This data is collected for system security verification only.Cookies: Cookies are small text files containing an identifier that are stored on the visitor's computer in order to recognize them. Thus, the information contained in the cookies serve the session control.Users can regulate the use of cookies via their own browser and delete cookies at any time. If you do not allow cookies, you can still use our website without any restrictions.Matamo (Piwik): The website uses Matamo, which gathers information on cookies to conduct a statistical analysis of website usage. This involves the collection of usage information, whereby your IP address is immediately anonymized.Twitter: Functions of the Twitter service are integrated on our sites. These features are provided by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. By using Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" function, the websites you visit are linked to your Twitter account and shared with other users. This means that the following data can be collected by Twitter, including: Your IP address, browser type, operating system, information about previously visited websites and pages, your location, your wireless service provider, your device information (including device ID and application ID), search terms and cookie information. We would like to point out that we as the provider of the pages are not aware of the content of the transmitted data and their use by Twitter. For more information, please see Twitter’s privacy policy. You can change your privacy settings on Twitter in the account settings.Data processed for e-servicesThe e-information services (such as newsletters and invitations) sent out by the IHS will process your name, email address and any other information you have provided (such as areas of interest).Any information that you provide to us as part of the e-information services registration process (sent by email outside the website, in writing or via the online registration function on the website) will be treated responsibly by our employees and used only to the extent necessary for the purposes outlined.If you use the online login feature, the Double-Opt-In procedure will be used to ensure that you have actually invoked this function yourself; we will send you an e-mail with a confirmation link and will not send you a newsletter until you have activated the confirmation link. When using the online form, the following information is stored to ensure satisfactory operation:The IP address of the requesting computer, date and time of access, name and URL of the retrieved file, amount of data transferred, message whether the retrieval was successful, recognition data of the accessing browser and the operating system, website from which the access was made. These data will be deleted after 30 days. In addition, the service (e-service) you have registered for, which information you have provided and whether the registration has been confirmed, will be recorded. For technical reasons, it may be necessary for the Double-Opt-In procedure to retain information about whether a confirmation has been issued for more than 30 days. In this case, the data will be deleted at the latest after one year.These data will not be transmitted to third parties.Data processed during eventsThis section will elaborate on data processed during the course of organizing events, such as public lectures, workshops, conferences and meetings, the data disclosed by the participants (in particular name, electronic contact details, address, telephone number, employer or affiliation, billing and bank details, title and abstract of the presentation/paper/lecture, co-authors, date and place of the event, food intolerances), which are required for the purpose of organizing the event. Data gathered in relation to these events, particularly with regards to third-party services (such as hotel bookings), will only be passed on to the extent necessary for the performance of the service.As far as it is necessary for the program preparation and promotion of the event, data (in particular names of lecturers, discussants and co-authors, title of the lecture or the submitted writing, date and time) will be published (e.g. on our website).Privacy Policy for Video Communication ServicesIHS will make use of external cloud based and self-hosted video communication services to facilitate continued contact within the Institute and to external stakeholders. This extends to delivering lectures, workshops, and hosting meetings. Thus, individuals within and external to the Institute can participate virtually without needing to be physically present.The following personal data is processed for the purpose of organizing and handling meetings and (teaching) events (e.g. invitations to virtual conference rooms):Employees who have accounts set up through the IHS-IT service: first name, last name and email address.Participants in video conferences: self-selected pseudonyms or, if applicable, first and last names and email addresses.Any contributions and comments made during the virtual conference; all messages and their content communicated in a meeting, including personal data, are available to all other participants in this meeting.Any personal data and information that is uploaded, made available or created while using the service, including information related to meetings, such as participants, meeting URLs, date, time and duration.In addition, all activities (such as participation and leaving) are processed and the content of audio and video calls and screen shares between the call participants.Traffic and media data (IP address, information about your device, usage information, possibly the telephone number etc.).Traffic and usage data are processed to fulfill contractual obligations, in particular to ensure the trouble-free functioning of the services and to inform usage statistics.During calls or talks, participants can decide whether they want to activate their cameras or microphones.The legal basis for the processing of personal data is based on that the processing is necessary for the performance of a task that is in the public interest or to safeguard the legitimate interests of IHS, with regards to its teaching and research responsibilities, and to inform the public about its fulfillment of these duties, as well as, if applicable, the fulfillment of a contract or based on the consent of the participants (Article 6 (1) (a), (b), (e) and (f) GDPR).The recipients of the personal data are the organizational units of IHS involved in the correspondence as well as our processor Zoom and Microsoft. The manufacturer Zoom (Zoom Video Communications, Inc., 55 Almaden Boulevard, 6th Floor, San Jose, CA 95113, USA) processes data in the USA. The transmission takes place on the basis of the Privacy Shields Agreement (according to Art. 45 GDPR) and the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission (according to Art. 46 Para. 2 lit. c GDPR). Zoom's privacy policy can be found at https://zoom.us/de-de/privacy.htmlThe manufacturer Microsoft (Microsoft Corporation One Microsoft Way Redmond, WA 98052-6399 USA) processes data in the USA. The transmission takes place on the basis of the Privacy Shields Agreement (according to Art. 45 GDPR) and the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission (according to Art. 46 Para. 2 lit. c GDPR). Microsoft's privacy policy can be found at https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement#mainnoticetoendusersmoduleEvents that are aimed at the public can be broadcast via live stream on the Internet. For the purposes of documenting (teaching) events and the subsequent public relations work, the virtual conference may be recorded as a video and screenshots of the event or content may be taken, participants may be notified of this. Photos or videos of people can also be published on the Internet (especially on our website or social media channels). This is done on the basis of our legitimate interest (Art. 6 Para. 1 lit f GDPR) for the purpose of disseminating scientific research results in the public interest and for advertising related events.The storage period is determined in accordance with the defined criteria based on the purpose of the data, as well as in accordance with any statutory retention periods.Data protection in the application processThe IHS will not segregate or differentiate between individuals on the grounds of disability, gender or its expression, sexual orientation, age, social class, national origin, religion, ethnicity or ethnic characteristics, but advocates equality and diversity. We do not require any information from you which cannot be used in accordance with the General Equal Treatment Act under Austrian law or the International Equal Treatment Act.Declaration of ConsentBy submitting your application documents, you agree that the personal data you have provided, such as: First and last name, title, gender, date of birth, nationality, address, marital status, legal employment requirements, completed military service, driver's license, education and professional background, language skills and subject knowledge, position details, availability information, salary expectations and supporting documents (such as CV, cover letter, certificates) is being processed, recorded, stored and kept by the IHS for the purpose of processing your application or for candidate selection. The processing of this personal data takes place exclusively for the purpose of processing the application or the applicant selection.IHS employees involved in the selection process are obliged to handle and process your data securely. These persons will ensure that the confidentiality of the data is maintained, within the scope of the intended use. Your data will not be transmitted to third parties.Your data will be kept for the duration of the application process, any subsequent employment and after the application and/or employment, the data will be held for the duration of the respective statutory retention period. If there is no legal justification for storage, the retention period of a rejected application is 7 months. An automatically sent notification to you about the destruction of the data will not occur.Data that the IHS processes as part of its research activitiesThe responsible handling of data that is processed as part of research is of great importance to the IHS and its researchers. If data is not anonymized but processed with personal details, this is done only on the basis of legal provisions. If the data are collected directly from those affected, they will be informed about the purpose and use.Information pursuant to Art. 13 and Art. 14 GDPRRegardless of the purpose of the processing of data and the manner in which it is processed, the following rights exist within the legal scope:• The right to know if and what data is being processed.• The right to rectification.• The right to erasure.• The right to restrict processing.• The right to data portability.• If data has been transmitted to others, the right to be forgotten.• If the processing is based on your consent, you have the right to object to our processing of your data and withdraw consent. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.• The right to correction.Please contact dsgvo(at)ihs.ac.at to exercise these rights.Please note that in order to fulfill your request, we may require proof of your identity in the form of an electronic signature or ID card copy.Furthermore, you have the right to file a complaint with the Austrian Data Protection Authority, Barichgasse 40-42, 1030 Vienna, Austria, dsb(at)dsb.gv.at.DisclaimerWhen publishing photos, videos or other information on its publicly accessible website and its social media channels, IHS naturally complies with the applicable data protection and other legal obligations. However, IHS has no influence whatsoever on third parties who link this information to other information and may also copy and process it for other purposes not covered by this privacy policy. IHS accepts no liability for such actions.Changes in our privacy policyIn order to ensure that our privacy policy always complies with current legal requirements, we reserve the right to make changes at any time. This also applies in the event that the privacy policy is changed due to new or revised services and requires an adaptation. If we change our policy, the new privacy policy will take effect the next time you visit our website.A note on language versionIn case of dispute the German language version shall prevail.
